gonomad.com 2018-10-08

# Our Privacy Policy - GoNOMAD Travel

By visiting this website, you consent to the collection and use of your Personal Data as described herein. If you do not agree with the terms set out herein, please do not visit this website. If required by applicable law, we will seek your explicit consent to process Personal Data collected on this website or volunteered by you. Kindly note that any consent will be entirely voluntary. However, if you do not grant the requested consent to the processing of your Personal Data, the use of this website may not be possible.

GoNOMAD.com may collect, record and analyze information of Visitors to its website. We may record your IP address and use cookies. GoNOMAD.com may add information collected by way of pageview activity. Furthermore, GoNOMAD.com may collect and process any Personal Data that you volunteer to us in our website’s forms, such as when you register for events or sign up for information and newsletters. If you provide GoNOMAD.com with your social media details, GoNOMAD.com may retrieve publicly available information about you from social media.

Such Personal Data may comprise your IP address, first and last name, your postal and email address, your telephone number, your job title, data for social networks, your areas of interest, interest in GoNOMAD.com products, and certain information about the company you are working for (company name and address), as well as information as to the type of relationship that exists between GoNOMAD.com and yourself.

GoNOMAD.com gathers data about visits to the website, including numbers of Visitors and visits, Geo-location data, length of time spent on the site, pages clicked on or where Visitors have come.

2.2.1 Purpose of processing personal data  
GoNOMAD.com uses the collected data to communicate with Visitors, to customize content for Visitors, to show ads on other websites to Visitors, and to improve its website by analyzing how Visitors navigate its website.

2.2.2 Sharing personal data  
GoNOMAD.com may also share such information with service vendors or contractors in order to provide a requested service or transaction or in order to analyze the Visitor behavior on its website.

2.2.3 Cookies  
Cookies are small pieces of information sent by a website to a Visitor’s hard disk. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. By continuing to visit the website, you agree to the placement of cookies on your device. If you choose not to accept our cookies, we cannot guarantee that your experience will be as fulfilling as it would otherwise be. We may also place cookies from third parties for functional and marketing purposes. The use of cookies is widespread and benefits the surfer. For further information, see GoNOMAD.com Cookie Policy.

2.2.4 Links to other sites  
Please be aware that while visiting our site, Visitors can follow links to other sites that are beyond our sphere of influence. GoNOMAD.com is not responsible for the content or privacy policy of these other sites.

2.3 Respondents  
Respondents should be aware that in responding to surveys or survey invitations, they could be disclosing information that could make them personally identifiable to GoNOMAD.com Users. The security and privacy protection implemented on GoNOMAD.com’s platform does not cover this type of transfer or disclosure of personal information. Respondents responding to surveys or survey invitations should be aware that they alone are responsible for the content of their responses.

For more detailed information concerning the protection of privacy when responding to surveys or survey invitations, Respondents may contact the entity conducting the survey. It is the User’s responsibility to ensure that collection and processing of data are done in accordance with applicable law. GoNOMAD.com will not process Personal Data of Respondents for other purposes or by other means than instructed by its Users.

2.3.1. Inquires  
If you wish to inquire about your Personal Data that may have been collected in a GoNOMAD.com survey, we recommend that you contact the entity that created or sent you the survey. As GoNOMAD.com is a Processor, it does not control the Personal Data used or stored in the survey but processes it on behalf of its User.

2.4 Users  
2.4.1. General  
In order to provide services to its Users, GoNOMAD.com collects certain types of data from them. We collect information from Respondents when they produce and distribute surveys. This section will describe how these two types of data are collected and used by GoNOMAD.com as well as geographical differences that affect this policy. Data entered or transferred into GoNOMAD.com by Users such as texts, questions, contacts, media files, etc., remains the property of the User and may not be shared with a third party by GoNOMAD.com without express consent from the User.

2.4.2 Collection of User data  
During a User’s registration and later on GoNOMAD.com’s platform, they provide information such as name, company name, email, address, telephone, credit-card number and other relevant data. This information is used by GoNOMAD.com to identify the User and provide them with support, services, mailings, sales and marketing actions, billing and to meet contractual obligations.

GoNOMAD.com Users can at any time access and edit, update or delete their contact details by logging in with their username and password to GoNOMAD.com’s platform. GoNOMAD.com Users may create more Users with different privilege levels within their account. It is the responsibility of the User that creates other User accounts, to choose the level of access each User should have. Once these new Users log into GoNOMAD.com, they meet the definition of User in this policy. GoNOMAD.com will not retain User data longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations.

2.4.3 Collection of Respondent data  
Surveys used for gathering feedback are created by Users, who make them available to relevant businesses, organizations, and individuals. It is the User’s responsibility to ensure that collection and processing of data are done in accordance with applicable law. GoNOMAD.com will not process Personal Data for other purposes or by other means than instructed by its Users.

Respondent data includes data from individuals uploaded, transferred or manually entered by a GoNOMAD.com User into their account for the purpose of providing feedback to the User by responding to surveys. Personal Data may include, personal contact information such as name, home address, home telephone or mobile number, email address, business contact details and other sensitive Personal Data. Answers to questions by Respondents may also include Personal Data.

The purpose of collecting Personal Data as part of a survey will vary depending on the survey, as set up by GoNOMAD.com’s Users. As GoNOMAD.com provides surveys to a wide group of customers and businesses, the purpose may vary greatly. For Users in the EEA, or for Users providing surveys to Respondents in the EEA, the User will be the “controller”, as defined in the Directive and the GDPR. The purpose will consequently be defined by GoNOMAD.com’s User.

If you or your organization are required under the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) to enter into a contract, or other binding legal act under EU or Member State law, with your data processors, review and accept GoNOMAD.com’s Data Processing Agreement in your GoNOMAD.com account.

2.4.4. Geographical location  
GoNOMAD.com is located in South Deerfield MA, but our server is located in Virginia, in the United States of America (US). All Personal Data is processed solely in the respective country.

2.4.4.1 Processing in the European Economic Area (EEA)  
For Users with accounts located in GoNOMAD.com’s European Data Region, all processing of Personal Data is performed in accordance with privacy rights and regulations following the EU Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995 (the Directive), and the implementations of the Directive in local legislation. From May 25th, 2018, the Directive and local legislation based on the Directive will be replaced by the Regulations (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of Personal Data and on the free movement of such data, known as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and GoNOMAD.com’s processing will take place in accordance with the GDPR.

2.4.4.1.1 Controller  
GoNOMAD.com processes Personal Data both as a Processor and as a Controller, as defined in the Directive and the GDPR:

The GoNOMAD.com entity which you as a User entered an agreement with when using GoNOMAD.com’s platform, will be the Controller for User data, as outlined above in “Collection of User data” section.  
For Respondent data, as outlined in the “Collection of Respondent data” section, the User will be the Controller in accordance with Directive and GDPR, and GoNOMAD.com will be the Processor.  
GoNOMAD.com adheres to the Directive of 1995 and the GDPR from May 25th, 2018. Consequently, GoNOMAD.com processes all data provided by its Users with accounts in its European Data Region, in the European Economic Area (EEA) only.

All data collected by GoNOMAD.com Users through surveys will be stored exclusively in secure hosting facilities in the United States of America. GoNOMAD.com has a data processing agreement in place with its provider, ensuring compliance with the Directive. All hosting is performed in accordance with the highest security regulations. All transfers of data internally in the EEA is done in accordance with this data processing agreement.

2.4.4.2 Processing in the United States Of America (US)  
For Users with accounts in the GoNOMAD.com US Data Region, GoNOMAD.com processes data solely in data centers located in the US. GoNOMAD.com has adopted reasonable physical, technical and organizational safeguards which substantially mirror the EU safeguards against accidental, unauthorized or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, disclosure, access, use or processing of the User’s data in GoNOMAD.com’s possession. GoNOMAD.com will promptly notify the User in the event of any known unauthorized access to, or use of, the User’s data.

All data collected by GoNOMAD.com Users through surveys will be stored exclusively in secure hosting facilities in the United States of America. GoNOMAD.com’s contract with its hosting provider ensures that all hosting is performed in accordance with the highest security regulations. GoNOMAD.com’s policy is to protect and safeguard any personal information obtained by GoNOMAD.com in accordance with United States state or federal laws governing the protection of personal information and data. Accordingly, GoNOMAD.com adheres to practices and policies that aim to safeguard the data.

All data collected by GoNOMAD.com Users through surveys will be stored exclusively in secure hosting facilities.  Our contract with its hosting provider ensures that all hosting is performed in accordance with the highest security regulations. Accordingly, GoNOMAD.com adheres to practices and policies that aim to safeguard the data.

3\. Retention and deletion  
GoNOMAD.com will not retain data longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations. For Respondent data, GoNOMAD.com’s Users have control of the purpose for collecting data, and the duration for which the Personal Data may be kept. For Respondent data, Users with an active account will therefore have the responsibility to delete data when required. When a users’s account is terminated or expired, all Personal Data collected through the platform will be deleted, as required by applicable law.

4\. Acceptance of these Conditions  
We assume that all Visitors of our website, Respondents to surveys powered by GoNOMAD.com and users GoNOMAD.com’s platform have carefully read this document and agree to its contents. If someone does not agree with this privacy policy, they should refrain from using our website and platform. We reserve the right to change our privacy policy as necessity dictates. Continued use of GoNOMAD.com website and platform after having been informed of any such changes to these conditions implies acceptance of the revised privacy policy. This privacy policy is an integral part of GoNOMAD.com’s terms of use.

5\. Our Legal Obligation to Disclose Personal Information  
We will reveal a user’s personal information without his/her prior permission only when we have reason to believe that the disclosure of this information is required to establish the identity of, to contact or to initiate legal proceedings against a person or persons who are suspected of infringing rights or property belonging to GoNOMAD.com or to others who could be harmed by the user’s activities or of persons who could (deliberately or otherwise) transgress upon these rights and property. We are permitted to disclose personal information when we have good reason to believe that this is legally required.
